Highest Degree: MCA [Computers]

# Anjali Bhatnagar (1) Featured

Associate Consultant - IT seeking roles in Software Development, Application Programming, System Analysis, Project Management, Technical Architecture, Requirement Gathering, Performance Tuning, Release Management, SQL, PLSQL, Oracle



Current Designation: Associate Consultant - IT Total Experience: 4 Year(s) 4 Month(s)

Current Company: Capgemini Technology Services India Notice Period: 1 Month

Limited Current Location: Pune

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Delhi / NCR, Pune Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Associate Consultant - IT, Software Developer, Software Development, Application Programming, System Analysis, Project Management, Technical Architecture, Requirement Gathering, Performance Tuning, Release

Management, SQL, PLSQL, Oracle

Verified: Phone Number 1 Email - id

Last Active: 20-Jan-21 Last Modified: 20-Jan-21

# Summary

Have experience of 4.4 years in the Software Industry.

Currently working in Capgemini Ltd. as an Associate Consultant.

Had worked in Infosys Ltd. as a System Engineer.

Have understanding of technology with focus on delivering business solutions.

Persuasive communicator with exceptional relationship management skills with the ability to relate to people at any level of business and management.

Friendly, ethical, trustworthy and discreet with an upbeat attitude

# Work Experience

#### Capgemini Technology Services India Limited as Associate Consultant - IT Apr 2019 to Till Date

Manulife 1)

Creating database objects such as tables, views, synonyms, indexes.

Modifying stored procedures, functions, packages, views and SQL queries as per the new business requirements / changes.

Improving the performance of the application by rewriting the SQL queries.

Involved in full development cycle of Planning, Analysis, Design, Development Testing and Implementation.

Developing and modifying triggers, packages, functions and stored procedures for data conversions and PL/SQL procedures to create database objects dynamically based on user inputs.

Implementing the new changes and working on Defect Fixing.

Working with Bulk Collects to improve the performance of multi-row queries by reducing the context switching. Working with Exception Handling Techniques to handle the runtime errors.

Creating indexes on tables to improve the performance by eliminating the full table scans and views for hiding the actual tables and to eliminate the complexity of the large queries.

Infosys Ltd. as System Engineer Sep 2016 to Mar 2019

Capital Group of Companies (CGC) 1)

Built and maintained SQL scripts, indexes, reports and queries for data analysis and extraction.

Wrote queries and handled backend part of the reporting which includes requirement gathering, writing script's using procedures, functions, cursors with Developers.

Analyzed logs to troubleshoot the error.

Provided access to the users to the required database servers and removing their access when they leave the company.

Duration: April 2017 - till 11 March 2019

Designation: Testing Executive

Finacle Solutions [EdgeVerve]

Creation of documents for 2017 release.

Analyzing the errors in the document of previous releases and correcting in the new release.

Creation of help files using RoboHelp.

Creation of screenshots so that users can understand how to work on Finacle Software.

Duration: January 2017 - April 2017

#### **Education**

UG: BCA (Computers) from MAHAVEER Teerthanker Mahaveer Institute of Management & Technology, Moradabad in 2016

PG: MCA (Computers) from Sikkim Manipal University (SMU) in 2021

### IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Exp	erience
Oracle: SQL and PL/SQL		
Oracle Database 10g/11g		

## Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				

#### **Affirmative Action**

Category: General

Job Type: Permanent

Physically Challenged: No

Employment Status: Full time

**Work Authorization**